William R. Davey Papers
William R. Davey Papers
1894-1963
Davey, William R.
5.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American educator, includes correspondence (1894-1963); lesson plan notebooks; photographs; and financial records.
148929
Biographical History
William R. Davey was Professor of Classics at Syracuse University from 1911-1940.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William R. Davey Papers includes correspondence, scrapbooks, general subject files, lesson plans, lesson plan notebooks, and manuscripts and financial ledgers.
Correspondence is both incoming and outgoing. Of particular note is the correspondence with American author Theodore Dreiser. Other notable correspondents include Elizabeth Cleasby, Harold W. and Mary Davey, Helen (Patges) Dreiser, and Phyllis F. Field.
Scrapbooks, cards and postcards contains various memorabilia and souvenir items. Postcards are blank.
General subject files contains announcements and brochures, bank statements, bills, income tax files, family legal documents, and a few writings by others (poetry by Elizabeth Cleasby Davis, for example).
Lesson plans contains notes and research material for lectures and a few student reports. The subject mattery is the history of the Church.
Manuscripts and financial ledgers consists of the manuscripts of Dr. Davey's dissertation entitled "Semitic Phallicism With Particular Reference to the Hebrews Preceded by a Sketch of Non-Semitic Phallicism," a manuscript on science and religion, and two financial ledgers.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence is arranged chronologically with the exception of the Theodore Dreiser letters, which appear at the end of the chronology but before the undated material. The remaining series are arranged alphabetically by topic or type of material.
Subject and Genre Headings
None; Davey, Elizabeth Cleasby, 1878-; Davey, William R. -- Archives.; Davey family.; Dreiser, Helen Patges, d. 1955.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Educators -- United States.; Bank statements.; Bankbooks.; Checks (bank checks); Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Greeting cards.; Lecture notes.; Photographs.; Educators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - 1894-1906, 5 items (Box 1)
  - 1907, 4 items (Box 1)
  - 1908, 1 items (Box 1)
  - 1909, 6 items (Box 1)
  - 1910, 6 items (Box 1)
  - 1911, 3 items (Box 1)
  - 1912, 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1913 (William Davey), 4 items (Box 1)
  - 1913, 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1914 (William Davey), 9 items (Box 1)
  - 1914, 1 items (Box 1)
  - 1915, 1 items (Box 1)
  - 1916, 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1917, 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1918, 1 items (Box 1)
  - 1919, 8 items (Box 1)
  - 1920, 4 items (Box 1)
  - 1921, 5 items (Box 1)
  - 1922, 6 items (Box 1)
  - 1924, 5 items (Box 1)
  - 1925, 1 items (Box 1)
  - 1926, 8 items (Box 1)
  - 1927, 10 items (Box 1)
  - 1928, 8 items (Box 1)
  - 1929, 3 items (Box 1)
  - 1930, 15 items (Box 1)
  - 1931, 15 items (Box 1)
  - 1932, 7 items (Box 1)
  - 1933, 12 items (Box 1)
  - 1934, 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1934 (Phyllis Field), 41 items (Box 1)
  - 1935, 6 items (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Elizabeth Davey), 31 items (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Harold Davey), 4 items (Box 1)
  - 1935 (William Davey), 2 items (Box 1)
  - 1935 (Phyllis Field), 48 items (Box 1)
  - 1936, 22 items (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Elizabeth Davey), 3 items (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Harold Davey), 8 items (Box 1)
  - 1936 (Phyllis Field), 39 items (Box 1)
  - 1937, 19 items (Box 2)
  - 1937 (Elizabeth and William), 2 items (Box 2)
  - 1937 (Harold Davey), 7 items (Box 2)
  - 1938, 5 items (Box 2)
  - 1938 (Elizabeth Davey), 1 items (Box 2)
  - 1938 (William Davey), 7 items (Box 2)
  - 1939, 3 items (Box 2)
  - 1939 (Harold Davey), 4 items (Box 2)
  - 1939 (William,Davey), 11 items (Box 2)
  - 1940, 28 items (Box 2)
  - 1940 (Elizabeth Davey), 1 items (Box 2)
  - 1940 (William Davey), 1 item (Box 2)
  - 1940 (Harold Davey), 34 items (Box 2)
  - 1941, 9 items (Box 2)
  - 1941 (Elizabeth Davey), 2 items (Box 2)
  - 1941 (Harold Davey), 6 items (Box 2)
  - 1942, 9 items (Box 2)
  - 1942 (Harold and Mary Davey), 32 items (Box 2)
  - 1943, 9 items (Box 2)
  - 1943 (Mary Davey), 2 items (Box 2)
  - 1944, 3 items (Box 2)
  - 1944 (Harold and Mary Davey), 6 items (Box 2)
  - 1944 (Dr. Donald McCord), 3 items (Box 2)
  - 1945, 2 items (Box 2)
  - 1945 (Harold Davey), 8 items (Box 2)
  - 1945 (Dr. Donlad McCord), 1 items (Box 2)
  - 1946, 6 items (Box 2)
  - 1946 (Harold and Mary Davey), 9 items (Box 2)
  - 1947, 2 items (Box 2)
  - 1947 (Elizabeth DaveY), 1 items (Box 2)
  - 1947 (Harold and Mary Davey), 18 items (Box 2)
  - 1948, 32 items (Box 2)
  - 1948 (Harold and Mary Davey), 7 items (Box 2)
  - 1949, 26 items (Box 2)
  - 1949 (Harold and Mary Davey), 20 items (Box 2)
  - 1950, 22 items (Box 3)
  - 1950 (Harold and Billy Davey), 21 items (Box 3)
  - 1951, 15 items (Box 3)
  - 1951 (Harold and Mary Davey), 24 items (Box 3)
  - 1952, 25 items (Box 3)
  - 1952 (Harold and Mary and Billy Davey) (Box 3)
  - 1953, 31 items (Box 3)
  - 1953 (Harold Davey), 14 items (Box 3)
  - 1954, 17 items (Box 3)
  - 1954 (Harold and Billy Davey), 32 items (Box 3)
  - 1955, 37 items (Box 3)
  - 1955 (Harold and Billy Davey), 39 items (Box 3)
  - 1956, 4 items (Box 3)
  - 1956 (Harold and Mary and Billy tavey), 35 items (Box 3)
  - 1957, 10 items (Box 3)
  - 1957 (Harold Davey), 32 items (Box 3)
  - 1958, 28 items (Box 3)
  - 1958 (Harold Davey), 39 items (Box 3)
  - 1959, 32 items (Box 3)
  - 1959 (Harold and Billy Davey), 7 items (Box 3)
  - 1960, 22 items (Box 4)
  - 1960 (Harold and Mary Davey), 11 items (Box 4)
  - 1961, 38 items (Box 4)
  - 1961 (Elizabeth Davey), 1 items (Box 4)
  - 1961 (Harold and Billy Davey), 20 items (Box 4)
  - 1962, 57 items (Box 4)
  - 1962 (Harold Davey), 34 items (Box 4)
  - 1963, 18 items (Box 4)
  - 1963 (Harold Davey), 30 items (Box 4)
  - Theodore Dreiser Letters, 1948-1952; undated
    - Outgoing (Elizabeth Davey), 1 items (Box 4)
    - Incoming (Helen Dreiser), 6 items (Box 4)
  - Undated (Bill Davey), 2 items (Box 4)
  - Undated (Elizabeth Davey), 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated (Harold Davey), 25 items (Box 4)
  - Undated (Harold Davey), 29 items (Box 4)
  - Undated (William Davey), 5 items (Box 4)
  - Undated, 3 items (Box 4)
  - Undated C, 4 items (Box 4)
  - Undated D, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated E, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated F, 10 items (Box 4)
  - Undated G, 2 items (Box 4)
  - Undated H, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated K, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated M, 11 items (Box 4)
  - Undated 0, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated P, 2 items (Box 4)
  - Undated R, 2 items (Box 4)
  - Undated S, 9 items (Box 4)
  - Undated T, 1 items (Box 4)
  - Undated W, 3 items (Box 4)
  - Undated, Unsigned, 46 items (Box 4)
- Scrapbooks, cards, postcards
  - Scrapbook items
    - Greeting card postcards, 1906-1912; undated; 3 folders, 126 items (Box 5)
    - Photographs, 10 items (Box 5)
    - Souvenir pamphlets (photograph), 2 items (Box 5)
  - Greeting cards, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Postcards, 2 folders (Box 5)
- General files
  - Announcements, 1900-1963; undated; brochures, pamphlets, Programs; 6 folders (Box 6)
  - Announcements: insurance companies (stocks and bonds brokers) (Box 6)
  - Bank statements, 1900-1963; books, cancelled checks, etc.; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Bills, 1919-1963; undated; 4 folders; notices, receipts, miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Cleasby, Harold Loomis: "Salutory Address", April 27, 1894; holograph; also includes newspaper clipping (Box 7)
  - Davey, Elizabeth Cleasby
    - Poetry, includes 3 original typescript manuscripts with corrections; 8 carbon copy manuscripts with corrections; 1 holographic manuscript; 2 published manuscripts; 6 miscellaneous poetry notes (holograph and typescript); 20 items (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 1942-1962; undated; 8 items (Box 7)
  - Davey, Harold
    - Miscellaneous, 1912-1962; undated; announcements, notebooks, programs, souvenirs; 15 items (Box 7)
    - Reports of Academic Rating and Diplomas (Honor Societies), 1931-1936; 35 items (Box 7)
    - Writings, 1946-1950; carbon copy manuscript; mimeographed reports; 6 items (Box 7)
    - Writings, 1956-1962; undated; newspaper clippings; holographic manuscripts; carbon copy manuscripts; published copies; 9 items (Box 7)
  - Davey, William, 1909-1932; certificates and program; 4 items (Box 7)
  - Datebook (diary) for 1925 and miscellaneous notebooks and address books, undated; 8 items (Box 7)
  - Income tax, 1940-1955; correspondence; forms; miscellaneous bills, etc.; incoming correspondence; 13 items (Box 7)
  - Inventory of furnishings at 1024 Lancaster Avenue (Syracuse, N. Y.), typescript lists (Box 7)
  - Kiplinger Washington Letter news releases, 1962-1963 (Box 7)
  - Legal, photographs and miscellaneous
    - Family legal matters, 1924-1962; contracts, settlements, wills; 18 items (Box 8)
    - Old magazine and newspaper clippings, 1889-1920; undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Magazine and newspaper clippings, 1934-1962; undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Photographs, 120 items, 3 folders (Box 8)
    - Miscellaneous, 1896-1963; undated; anecdotes, notes, poems, recipes, souvenirs, etc.; 2 folders (Box 8)
- Lesson plans of Dr. Davey
  - Bibliographies and subject outlines (typescript) (Box 9)
  - Holographic notes on the Church (Box 9)
  - Holographic lecture notes, 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Source material for lectures (Box 9)
  - Student reports (Box 9)
  - Holographic lecture notes on Church history, 1902; 1904,; 1905; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Lecture notebooks of Dr. Davey, 1905-1907; undated; 5 notebooks (Box 10)
- Manuscripts and financial ledgers
  - Doctoral degree manuscripts and notebooks, entitled in first and and second drafts for Howard University "Semitic Phallicism With Particular Reference to the Hebrews Preceded by a Sketch of Non-Semitic Phallicism"; 2 volumes (Box 11)
  - Untitled holographic manuscript on science and religion, 17 pp. (Box 11)
  - Financial ledgers (notebooks), 1916-1926; 2 volumes (Box 11)